<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>vb YAZILIM - Blog</title>
  <subtitle>Heavy development warning...</subtitle>
  <id>http://vbyazilim.com/</id>
  <link href="http://vbyazilim.com/"/>
  <link href="http://vbyazilim.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2019-06-01T10:00:00+03:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Uğur Özyılmazel</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>hello world</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://vbyazilim.com/posts/2019/06/01/hello-world/"/>
    <id>http://vbyazilim.com/posts/2019/06/01/hello-world/</id>
    <published>2019-06-01T10:00:00+03:00</published>
    <updated>2019-06-09T16:58:14+03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Uğur Özyılmazel</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello and welcome to our &lt;strong&gt;first&lt;/strong&gt; official blog post!
&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello and welcome to our &lt;strong&gt;first&lt;/strong&gt; official blog post!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="zoomable "&gt;&lt;figure class="image"&gt;&lt;img class="mini-zoom" src="/public/images/posts/2019-06-01-vbyazilim.jpg" alt="Image" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m Uğur “vigo” Özyılmazel and I’m a software developer and founder of &lt;strong&gt;vb
YAZILIM&lt;/strong&gt;. I’ve been writing code since the early 8-bit computer days.
I have a long running career for a 47 y/o developer. I’ve spend my last ~18
years with building web applications. Some of them were heavy, some of them
were super easy&amp;hellip; At the end of day, they were all html outputted web sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned a lot while building sites, apps and related things such as
operating systems, databases, saas platforms and more&amp;hellip; My journey started
with 6502 Assembly language&amp;hellip; Yes, &lt;strong&gt;Commodore 64&lt;/strong&gt; my first true &lt;span class="icon"&gt;&lt;i class="fas fa-heart"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.
Then 68000 Assembly language for coding demos, intros and games for &lt;strong&gt;AmigA&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;hellip;
I’m still using those awesome machines and there are still tons of new releases!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Django&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My curse, my gift&amp;hellip; I’ve been building Django applications since 2008. I remember
the version I met &lt;code&gt;Django==0.96&lt;/code&gt;. I witnessed the evolution of Django over the
years. It’s free and open source Python web-framework for everybody! I made
many web apps with PHP back-in days. First time I saw the Django Admin panel
and I crashed! I guess, that’s the most exciting feature! and very attractive&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made couple hundred web apps with Django over the years. I was working in a
University and I injected Python to our team. Sometimes small-mini web sites,
sometimes huge, heavy apps&amp;hellip; All done with Django&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Polyglot&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I heard this term from &lt;a href="https://www.kennethreitz.org"&gt;Kenneth Reitz&lt;/a&gt;. He was Python overlord at &lt;a href="https://heroku.com"&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt;
back in 2013. Yes, I’m also a polyglot programmer. This means, I know few other
programming languages too. I use Python, Ruby, Bash, AppleScript, sometimes
JavaScript (&lt;em&gt;not fan of It&lt;/em&gt;) and little bit of Golang in my daily routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very enthusiastic about learning new languages such as Swift, Rust.
Due to my oldskool background, I’ve never had a chance to code in compiled
languages such as C, C++. After Assembly, I’ve jumped straight to run-time,
script-ish languages such as ASP 3.0 (old, classic), PHP, Perl&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I meet Ruby in 2011 and that that was another ground breaking thing for me.
Blending my Python knowledge with Ruby opened my mind&amp;hellip; I followed the
pioneers of the industry. How they write code ? What are their best practices ?
Yes, conventions are always over the configurations!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What about vb YAZILIM ?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Founded in late 2013. Mostly known from smashing hit conferences between 2013
- 2015. We tried to help and support open-source related movements and
activities. We were two times sponsor of &lt;a href="http://railsgirls.com/"&gt;Rails Girls&lt;/a&gt; Istanbul and Ankara,
&lt;a href="https://ozgurwebgunleri.org.tr/2013/"&gt;Özgür Web Teknolojileri Günleri&lt;/a&gt; 2013, Rails Girls Summer of Code 2014,
&lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/jstanbul/"&gt;Jstanbul Meetup&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.meetup.com/IstanbulPHP/"&gt;PHP İstanbul&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Highly focused on heavy Django application development and weekend
training sessions. It’s been six years and finally I’ve managed to find
enough time to re-design, re-build my humble company website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll publish mostly development related articles, examples, reviews and
same sort of topics here in my company website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep following &lt;strong&gt;vb YAZILIM&lt;/strong&gt;, get in touch !&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
